

SHAZID HASAN RIAM

Graphic & UI Designer Front-End Developer

ABOUT ME

Creative Graphic and User Interface Designer & Front-End Developer with two years facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software. Experienced in designing print and digital media materials. Maintains user-centric designs while adhering to prescribed interface principles and related development goals. Efficient problem solver with skills in teamwork and delivering projects on time.

CONTACT ME

Phone:

01717 435 769 01600 009 785

Address:

House: 21, Road: 05, Block: B, Banasree, Rampura, Dhaka - 1219

Email:

shazidhasanriam@gmail.com shazid.riam@northsouth.edu

EXPERIENCES

MAR, 2021 - OCT, 2021

User Interface Designer Ghuddy Limited

- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Analyzed existing interfaces to detect user pain points, recommending design changes and iterative updates to the IT manager.

NOV, 2019 - FEB, 2020

Graphic Designer North South University

- Worked with clients to gather and define requirements, establish scopes and managing project milestones.
- Designed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks.
- Completed in-depth product design tests with help of different software, models and design systems.

PUBLICATION

01. Mohammad Ashraful Haque Abir, Golam Kibria Anik, **Shazid Hasan Riam**, Mohammed Ariful Karim, Azizul Hakim Tareq, Rashedur M. Rahman, **Skin Disease Classification Using Machine Learning Techniques** - IWANN 2021: International Work Conference on Artificial Neural Networks DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-85030-2_49

PROJECTS

Personal Website

- I have designed the user interface of my website using Adobe XD
- Developed the website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- The website is responsive for various devices
- Available light and dark mode
- Multiple color themes are available

Languages/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Link: https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/PersonalPortfolio/

Bookmark Manager

- Users can manage all their bookmarks in one place
- Easy to add and remove bookmarks
- Bookmarks are saved on the local device

Languages/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Link: https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/BookmarkManager/

Form Validator

- Basic form validation for signing up
- Ensures email, website, phone number is in the correct format
- Check and confirm password while creating

Languages/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Link: https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/FormValidator/

EDUCATION

APR, 2016 - JAN, 2022

B.Sc - Computer Science & Engineering

North South University CGPA: 3.03 (83% Marks)

JAN, 2011 - MAR, 2013

SSC - Science

Bindu Basini Govt. Boys' High School

GPA: 5.00

APR, 2013 - MAR, 2015

HSC - Science

Major General Mahmudul Hasan Adarsha College

GPA: 5.00

PORTFOLIO

Behance:

https://www.behance.net/shazidhasanriam

Github:

https://github.com/ShazidHasanRiam

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shazidhasanriam

Portfolio Website:

https://shazidhasanriam.github.io/PersonalPortfolio

HOBBIES

Cycling Travelling Photography

SKILLS

Graphic Design

• Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom

User Interface Design

• Adobe XD

Front-End Development

• HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

TRAININGS

MAR, 2018 - SEP, 2018

Graphic & UI Design

Shikhbe Shobai Duration: 4 Months

JUL 25, 2017 - NOV 11, 2017

Graphic & Web UI Design

BASIS Institute Of Technology & Management

Duration: 140 Hours

APR, 2017 - AUG, 2018

Professional Web Design

UY Lab

Duration: 4 Months

REFERENCES

Jamil Ahmed

Eisenhower Fellow - USA Director - Public Relations Office North South University

Phone: 01711 855 732

Email: directorpr@northsouth.edu

Saiful Haque Miraz

Founder & CEO Ghuddy Limited Phone: 01717 855 156

Email: miraz@ghuddy.com